<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Plugins on Alexandre Neto</title><link>https://srnetochan.github.io/posts/plugins/</link><description>Recent content in Plugins on Alexandre Neto</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://srnetochan.github.io/posts/plugins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Multipart Split</title><link>https://srnetochan.github.io/posts/plugins/multipart-split/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 08:41:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://srnetochan.github.io/posts/plugins/multipart-split/</guid><description>&lt;p>This QGIS plugin Multipart Split allows the user to, during edition, split the active layer’s selected multipart features into single part features. Unlike the “Multipart to single part” from the Vector &amp;gt; Geometry Tools menu, the plugin only splits the selected elements, and does not need to create new files.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="installation">Installation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The plugin is available in the QGIS official repository, therefore the installation is done in the Manage and Install Plugins (Plugins &amp;gt; Manage and Install plugins…).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Walking time</title><link>https://srnetochan.github.io/posts/plugins/walking-time/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 08:41:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://srnetochan.github.io/posts/plugins/walking-time/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;strong>Walking time&lt;/strong> is a QGIS python plugin that uses Tobbler’s hiking function to estimate the travel time along a line depending on the slope.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The input data required are a vector layer with lines and a raster layer with elevation values ​​(1). One can adjust the base velocity (on flat terrain) according to the type of walking or walker. By default, the value used is 5 km h (2). The plugin update or create fields with estimated time in minutes in forward and in reverse direction (3). One can run the plugin for all elements of the vector layer, or only on selected routes (4).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>