<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Conda on Alexandre Neto</title><link>https://srnetochan.github.io/tags/conda/</link><description>Recent content in Conda on Alexandre Neto</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 01:32:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://srnetochan.github.io/tags/conda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create a PyQGIS Development Environment Using Conda and VScode</title><link>https://srnetochan.github.io/posts/tutorials/2024-05-11-create-easy-pyqgis-developement-environment-using-conda-and-vscode/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 01:32:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://srnetochan.github.io/posts/tutorials/2024-05-11-create-easy-pyqgis-developement-environment-using-conda-and-vscode/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a self-taught PyQGIS developer, one of my main hurdles has always been to
prepare the development environment for PyQGIS. An environment that allow me to run PyQGIS scripts, helps me
code faster by providing PyQGIS highlighting and autocompletion, enables me to
debug my plugins and scripts as they run, etc&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been a user (and even a&amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;cof cof&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip; maintainer) of the QGIS packages
for conda provided by the &lt;a href="https://conda-forge.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">conda-forge&lt;/a> community. In Linux, it has allowed me to
easily install the LTR version of QGIS (or any other version) alongside the most recent QGIS version
provided by qgis.org apt repositories. I ended up finding that this was quite convenient for development too.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using QGIS from conda-forge</title><link>https://srnetochan.github.io/posts/tutorials/2019-05-29-using-qgis-from-conda/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 22:46:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://srnetochan.github.io/posts/tutorials/2019-05-29-using-qgis-from-conda/</guid><description>&lt;p>QGIS recipes have been available on Conda-forge for a while, but now, that they work for the three main operating systems, installing QGIS from Conda is s starting to become a very reliable alternative to other QGIS distributions. Anyway, let&amp;rsquo;s rewind a bit&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is Conda?&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>Conda is an open source package management system and environment management system that runs on Windows, macOS and Linux. Conda quickly installs, runs and updates packages and all their dependencies. Conda easily creates, saves, loads and switches between environments on your local computer. It was created for Python packages, but it can package and distribute software for any language.&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>What is Conda-forge?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>