<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cartography on Alexandre Neto</title><link>http://srnetochan.github.io/tags/cartography/</link><description>Recent content in Cartography on Alexandre Neto</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 23:44:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://srnetochan.github.io/tags/cartography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hack to adjust map symbols location in QGIS</title><link>http://srnetochan.github.io/posts/tutorials/2015-02-23-dica-para-ajustar-posicao-de-simbolos-em-qgis-hack-to-adjust-map-symbols-location-in-qgis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 23:44:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://srnetochan.github.io/posts/tutorials/2015-02-23-dica-para-ajustar-posicao-de-simbolos-em-qgis-hack-to-adjust-map-symbols-location-in-qgis/</guid><description>EN | PT
Now and then I get too many map symbols (points) in the same place, and I thought how nice it would be if we could drag n' drop them around without messing with their geometries position, just like we do with labels. That thought gave me an idea for a cool hack.
Choose your point layer and start by creating two new fields called symbX and symbY (Type: Decimal number; Size: 20; Precision: 5).</description></item><item><title>Labels leading lines with QGIS and Postgis</title><link>http://srnetochan.github.io/posts/tutorials/2015-01-12-etiquetas-com-guias-em-qgis-e-postgis-labels-leading-lines-with-qgis-and-postgis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 08:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://srnetochan.github.io/posts/tutorials/2015-01-12-etiquetas-com-guias-em-qgis-e-postgis-labels-leading-lines-with-qgis-and-postgis/</guid><description>EN | PT
Recently I had the need to add labels to features with very close geometries, resulting in their collision.
Using data-defined override for label&amp;rsquo;s position (I have usedlayer to labeled layer plugin to set this really fast) and the QGIS tool to move labels, it was quite easy to relocate them to better places. However, in same cases, it was difficult to understand to which geometry they belonged.</description></item><item><title>Multiple format map series using QGIS 2.6 - Part 1</title><link>http://srnetochan.github.io/posts/tutorials/2014-11-09-series-de-mapas-com-formatos-multiplos-em-qgis-2-6-parte-1-multiple-format-map-series-using-qgis-2-6-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2014 23:07:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://srnetochan.github.io/posts/tutorials/2014-11-09-series-de-mapas-com-formatos-multiplos-em-qgis-2-6-parte-1-multiple-format-map-series-using-qgis-2-6-part-1/</guid><description>EN | PT
As always, the new QGIS version (QGIS 2.6 Brigthon) brings a vast new set of features that will allow the user to do more, better and faster than with the earlier version. One of this features is the ability to control some of the composer&amp;rsquo;s items properties with data (for instance, size and position). Something that will allow lots of new interesting usages. In the next posts, I propose to show how to create map series with multiple formats.</description></item><item><title>Map corner coordinates in QGIS</title><link>http://srnetochan.github.io/posts/tutorials/2014-09-09-coordenadas-dos-cantos-do-mapa-em-qgis-map-corner-coordinates-in-qgis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 23:05:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://srnetochan.github.io/posts/tutorials/2014-09-09-coordenadas-dos-cantos-do-mapa-em-qgis-map-corner-coordinates-in-qgis/</guid><description>EN | PT
Some time ago in the qgis-pt mailing list, someone asked how to show the coordinates of a map corners using QGIS. Since this features wasn&amp;rsquo;t available (yet), I have tried to reach a automatic solution, but without success, After some thought about it and after reading a blog post by Nathan Woodrow, it came to me that the solution could be creating a user defined function for the expression builder to be used in labels in the map.</description></item></channel></rss>