<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News on Alexandre Neto</title><link>https://srnetochan.github.io/posts/news/</link><description>Recent content in News on Alexandre Neto</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://srnetochan.github.io/posts/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>QGIS Top Features 2016</title><link>https://srnetochan.github.io/posts/news/2017-01-05-qgis-top-features-2016/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 01:51:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://srnetochan.github.io/posts/news/2017-01-05-qgis-top-features-2016/</guid><description>A year ago I have asked QGIS&amp;rsquo;s community what were their favourite QGIS new features from 2015 and published this blog post. This year I decided to ask it again. In 2016, we add the release of the second long-term release (2.14 LTR), and two other stable versions (2.16 and 2.18).
2016 was again very productive year for the QGIS community, with lots of improvements and new features landing on QGIS source code, not to speak of all the work already in place for QGIS 3.</description></item><item><title>QGIS Top Features 2015</title><link>https://srnetochan.github.io/posts/news/2016-01-01-qgis-top-features-2015/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 16:16:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://srnetochan.github.io/posts/news/2016-01-01-qgis-top-features-2015/</guid><description>With the release of the first long term release (2.8 LTR), and two other stable versions (2.10 and 2.12), 2015 was a great (and busy) year for the QGIS community, with lots of improvements and new features landing on QGIS source code.
As a balance, I have asked users to choose wich were their favorite new features during 2015 (from the visual changelogs list). As a result I got the following Top 5 features list.</description></item><item><title>New QGIS plugin - "Walking time"</title><link>https://srnetochan.github.io/posts/news/2014-03-25-novo-plugin-qgis-new-qgis-plugin-walking-time/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2014 08:41:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://srnetochan.github.io/posts/news/2014-03-25-novo-plugin-qgis-new-qgis-plugin-walking-time/</guid><description>I have finally &amp;ldquo;finished&amp;rdquo; my new plugin. I uses some quotation marks, since I believe that there is still space for a few improvement. This plugin arised with the need to calculate the travel time for the Cascais oficial pedestrian routes, and started as a simple python script. I have then decided to create a graphic interface and publish it as a plugin in the hope that someone else finds it useful.</description></item></channel></rss>